Welcome to the jingle.
Klaus is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Sergio Pablos.
A selfish postman and a reclusive toymaker form an unlikely friendship,
delivering joy to a cold, dark town that desperately needs it.
Jesper (voice), played by Jason Schwartzman.
Klaus (voice), played by J.K. Simmons.
Alva (voice), played by Rashida Jones.
Mrs. Krum (voice), played by Joan Cusack.
Mogens (voice), played by Norm Macdonald.
Mr. Ellingboe (voice), played by Will Sasso.
Klaus is a 2019  animated Christmas adventure comedy film co-written, co-produced, and directed by Sergio Pablos
in his directorial debut, produced by his company the SPA Studios and distributed by Netflix.
A traditionally animated film, it stars the voices of Jason Schwartzman, J.
Simmons, Rashida Jones, Will Sasso, Neda Margrethe Labba, Sergio Pablos (in a dual role), Norm
Macdonald (in his final film role released in his lifetime), and Joan Cusack.
Serving as an origin story of Santa Claus and using a fictionalized 19th-century setting, the plot revolves around
a postman stationed in an island town to the Far North who befriends a reclusive toymaker (Klaus).
Klaus was released on 8 November 2019 and received critical acclaim for its
animation, story, emotional depth, humor, narrative, and vocal performances.
It won seven awards at the 47th Annie Awards, including Best Animated Feature, and
also won Best Animated Film at the 73rd British Academy Film Awards.
The film was also nominated at the 92nd Academy Awards for Best Animated Feature, making it the first animated film from Netflix to be nominated for an Academy Award, as well as
the first animated film released by a streaming service to be nominated, alongside I Lost My Body (also Netflix), but lost to Toy Story 4, which also starred Cusack.
The film explores themes of friendship, small
town, island, holiday, santa claus.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.